Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Publications and Ephemera MC.334
New York University Archives
- RG 21.50. Department of Comparative Literature, 2017-ongoing
  - Department of Comparative Literature Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the Department of Comparative Literature at NYU. Contains listings related to events, job postings, film screenings, course listings, the Humanities Ambassadors Club, and conferences.
  - Department of Comparative Literature News, May 2022-ongoing
    Events and announcements from the New York University Department of Comparative Literature.
  - Department of Comparative Literature Twitter, May 2014-August 2015
    Twitter feed for the Department of Comparative Literature at NYU. Contains tweets related to events in 2013.
  - NYU Comparative Literature Newsletter, May 2022-ongoing
    Weekly newsletter for the Comparative Literature department at New York University.
- RG 21.52. Postdoctoral Program in Psychotherapy & Psychoanalysis, 2014-2018
  - Postdoctoral Program in Psychotherapy & Psychoanalysis Facebook, May 2014-November 2018
    Facebook page for the Postdoctoral Program in Psychotherapy & Psychoanalysis. Facebook posts include panel presentation descriptions, petitions, Psychoanalytic Dialogues, Psychoanalytic Fair, open houses, and other events.
  - Postdoctoral Program in Psychotherapy & Psychoanalysis Twitter, May 2014-November 2018
    Twitter feed for the Postdoctoral Program in Psychotherapy & Psychoanalysis. Tweets are related to conferences, psychoanalysis in pop culture, open houses, faculty research and articles, book reviews, Lacanian Works, and other article blurbs.
- RG 21.53. Department of Religious Studies, 2014-2015
  The Religious Studies Program explores religious practice as an important aspect of social life.
  - Department of Religious Studies Facebook, May 2014-May 2015
    The Facebook page holds event listings.
- RG 21.54. Department of Social & Cultural Analysis, 2014-2018
  - Department of Social & Cultural Analysis Facebook, May 2014-November 2018
    Facebook page for the Department of Social and Cultural Analysis (SCA). Includes departments such as Africana Studies, American Studies, Asian/Pacific/American Studies, Gender & Sexuality Studies, Latino Studies, and Metropolitan Studies. The Facebook page features colloquiums, lectures, course descriptions, film screenings, and other events.
- RG 22.0. School of Law, 1835-2022
  - Anglo-American Legal History, 1939-1944 (Box 163, Folder 9)
  - Annual and Review, 1922 (Box 163, Folder 10)
  - The Docket, May 2014-April 2019
    The Docket is a publication of New York University School of Law that publishes notices of NYU School of Law course announcements, administrative bulletins, announcements of events and other notices of general interest to the Law School community.
  - Environment and Land Use, May 2014-May 2018
    Blog for the Frank J. Guarini Center on Environmental and Land Use Law. The blog dates back to 2010.
    The Frank J. Guarini Center on Environmental and Land Use Law works to advance policy-relevant inquiry and writing to develop and implement innovative market and regulatory solutions for environmental, climate, and energy issues at the city, state, national, and global level.
  - Food Court, April-August 2014
    Food Court is written by Michael Orey, head of public affairs for NYU School of Law. Dates back to 2011.
  - From: The Tax Office, 1990 (Box 163, Folder 11)
  - Information Law Institute Student Blog, May 2014-April 2019
    Established initially as the Privacy Research Group Blog, the blog features posts related to behavioral advertising; government, technology, and policy; social media; and privacy tools. Blog posts date back to 2010. Blog changed its name in 2015.
  - Intramural Law Review, 1961-1965 (Box 168, Folder 1-2, Box 169)
  - The Law School Magazine, 1992-2009 (Box 170, Folder 7, Box 171, Folder 1-8, Box 172, Folder 1-7, Box 173, Folder 1-4)
  - New York University Law Center Bulletin, 1951-1974 (Box 168, Folder 3-6, Box 170, Folder 1-2)
  - New York University Review of Law and Social Change, 1989-1997 (Box 170, Folder 3-5)
  - NYU Law Magazine, May 2017-ongoing
    NYU School of Law's annual magazine, published each fall, has in-depth features on notable alumni or faculty members, academic areas, and other news. The magazine also publishes scholarly excerpts and newslength stories on the Law School's faculty, scholarship, programs, students, alumni, news, and events. The magazine online dates back to 2002.
  - N.Y.U. Lex / Lex, 1907 (Box 170, Folder 6)
  - Off the Record, 1987-1988 (Box 173, Folder 5)
  - School of Law Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the NYU School of Law. Post topics include information on deans, civil jury project, the bar exam, nonviolent offenders, racial inequality, Center on Law and Security, awards, clemency petitions, immigration, marriage equality, redistricting, student profiles, and other events.
  - School of Law Twitter, May 2014-August 2015
    Twitter feed of NYU School of Law. Tweet topics include race, copyright, education equality, environmental justice, Supreme Court opinions, faculty and student awards, Bryan Stevenson, marriage equality, human rights, immigration, graduation, international affairs, privacy, and other legal issues.
  - The Student Bar Reporter, 1966 (Box 173, Folder 6)
  - Tax Law Review, 1945-1946 (Box 173, Folder 7)
  - Transnational Notes, May 2014-ongoing
    Blog for the Center for Transnational Litigation, Arbitration and Commercial Law. The blog contains posts related to scholarship, faculty news, conflict laws, international arbitration, uniform law, and events. The blog date back to 2009.
    Biographical / Historical
    The Center for Transnational Litigation, Arbitration and Commercial Law was established to advance the study and practice of international business transactions and the way to solve related disputes either through litigation or arbitration.
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1835, 1890s, 1956 (Box 174, Folder 1-2)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1918-2012 (Box 174, Folder 11, Box 175, Folder 1-6, Box 176, Box 177, Folder 1-2)
  - Promotional Materials and Ephemera -- Posters, 1980-2001 (Box 195, Folder 1, Box 167, Folder 6)
  - Promotional Materials and Ephemera, 1998-2018 (Box 433, Folder 1-10, Box 434, Folder 1-9, Box 435, Box 436)
- RG 22.0.1. Tax Society (Promotional), 2000
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 2000 (Box 177, Folder 3)
- RG 22.3. Institute of Judicial Administration, 1952-2014
  - Criminal Justice Newsletter, 1970 (Box 177, Folder 4)
  - IJA Report, 1968-1990 (Box 177, Folder 5-6)
  - Institute of Judicial Administration Report, May 2014
    The IJA Report is the Newsletter of the Dwight D. Opperman Institute of Judicial Administration. It includes news updates Board, Members, Fellows, and Appellate Judges Seminar Alumni. The issues date from 2004-2008.
  - Institute of Judicial Administration Report, May 2014-ongoing
    The IJA Report is the Newsletter of the Dwight D. Opperman Institute of Judicial Administration. It includes news updates Board, Members, Fellows, and Appellate Judges Seminar Alumni. The issues dates back to 2004.
  - Institute of Judicial Administration Report Issuu, May 2023-ongoing
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1952-1995 (Box 177, Folder 7-12)
- RG 22.4. Criminal Law Education and Research Center, 1969-1971
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1969-1971 (Box 177, Folder 13)
- RG 22.5. Graduate Division, circa 1997-1998
  - NYU Law Tax Blog, March 2019
    The NYU Law Tax Blog contains the latest news about events and happenings at the NYU Graduate Tax Program. Includes information on career services, the international tax program, faculty and alumni news, scholarships, and other information. The blog dates back to 2010.
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, circa 1997-1998 (Box 177, Folder 14)
- RG 22.6. Inter-American Law Institute, 1952-1984
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1952-1984 (Box 177, Folder 15)
- RG 22.7. Institute of Comparative Law, circa 1955-1984
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, circa 1955-1984 (Box 178, Folder 1)
- RG 22.8. Citizenship Clearing House, 1950-1966
  - Citizenship, 1954-1959 (Box 178, Folder 2)
  - NCEP Bulletin, 1966 (Box 178, Folder 3)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1950-1952 (Box 178, Folder 4)
- RG 22.9. Civil Liberties Program, 1965, 2012, undated
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1965, 2012, undated (Box 178, Folder 5)
- RG 22.9.1. Project on Social Welfare, 1965-1969
  - Welfare Law Bulletin, 1965-1969 (Box 178, Folder 6-7)
- RG 22.10. Elihu Root-Samuel J. Tilden Scholarship Program, 1957-1998
  - Root-Tilden News / Root-Tilden-Snow Newsletter, 1977-1998 (Box 178, Folder 8-11)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1957-1979, 1992-1996, undated (Box 178, Folder 12-15)
- RG 22.11. The Juris Doctor Program, 1980-1998
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1980-1998 (Box 179, Folder 1-2)
- RG 22.13. Institute for Law and Society, 1995-1996, undated
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1995-1996, undated (Box 179, Folder 3)
- RG 22.14. Journals, 1986-1988, 1994-2019, 2021-ongoing
  - Annual Survey of American Law, 1996 (Box 179, Folder 4)
  - Clinical Law Review, 1995 (Box 179, Folder 5)
  - Clinical Law Review, May 2014-November 2019
    The Clinical Law Review (ISSN 1079-1159) is a semi-annual peer-edited journal devoted to issues of lawyering theory and clinical legal education. The Review is jointly sponsored by the Association of American Law Schools (AALS), the Clinical Legal Education Association (CLEA), and New York University School of Law. Articles date back to 2010.
  - Environmental Law Journal, 1994-1996 (Box 179, Folder 6)
  - Journal of International Law and Politics, 1996 (Box 179, Folder 7)
  - Journal of Law & Business, October 2021-ongoing
    NYU School of Law's Journal of Law & Business publishes articles at the intersection of law and business. Topics focused on in the journal include bankruptcy and restructuring; capital markets and securities; corporate law and governance; foreign and international business law; hedge funds and private equity; and tax. The Journal dates back to 2004. The blog on the website dates back to 2017.
  - Ephemera -- Banquet Program and Invitation, 1986, 1988 (Box 179, Folder 8)
- RG 22.15. Reiss Center for Law & Security, 2003-2015
  The Reiss Center for Law & Security is a research and policy institute dedicated to examining the legal and policy dimensions of national and global security. Posts focus on national security, counterterrorism, cybersecurity, legal, and foreign policy issues that arose in the aftermath of the 9/11 attacks.
  - Bulletin on Law and Security, 2004 (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - The NYU Review of Law and Security, 2003-2005 (Box 180, Folder 2)
  - Reiss Center on Law and Security Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the Center on Law and Security. It also includes event listings regarding conferences and book and panel discussions.
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 2004 (Box 180, Folder 3)
- RG 22.16. Center for Human Rights and Global Justice, 2004, 2014-2015
  - Center for Human Rights and Global Justice Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the Center for Human Rights and Global Justice. Includes call for submission for photography project, job opportunities, talk announcements, accolades for appointments, and reports.
  - Center for Human Rights and Global Justice Twitter, May 2014-May 2015
    Twitter feed for the Center for Human Rights and Global Justice at NYU Law. Tweet topics include global human rights, mass surveillance, inequality in health and wealth, tax justice, and job postings.
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 2004 (Box 180, Folder 4)
- RG 22.17. Hauser Global Law School Program, 1998-2002
  - Global Law, 1998-2002 (Box 180, Folder 5)
- RG 22.18. Public Interest Law Center (PILC), 1992-2019
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1992-2000, undated (Box 180, Folder 6)
- RG 22.19. Pro Bono Students America (PBSA), 1995-1997
  - Pro Bono Students American Newsletter, 1995-1997 (Box 180, Folder 7)
- RG 22.20. Master of Laws in International Taxation Program, 1996, undated
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1996, undated (Box 180, Folder 8)
- RG 22.21. Brennan Center for Justice, undated, 2014-2015
  The Brennan Center for Justice is a nonprofit organization that advocates for democratic legal reform including recent policy suggestions like automatic voter registration, small donor public financing, reversal of partisan gerrymandering, and prison reform to counter disenfranchisement and corporate influence over electoral politics.
  - Brennan Center for Justice, April 2019-ongoing
    The site features regular publication of articles and op-eds, policy solutions, research reports, and documentation of court cases. The site also has a directory of members and consulted experts categorized by issue area. Capture of this site began in April 2019. This description is based on a December 2019 capture of the site.
  - Brennan Center for Justice Blog, March 2019-February 2020
    Commentary is the blog for the Brennan Center for Justice. Topics on the blog include voting rights and elections, money in politics, government and court reform, the Second Amendment, justice for all, and liberty and national security.
  - Brennan Center for Justice Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook post topics include criminal justice reform, voting rights, surveillance and privacy, mass incarceration, and other news from the Center.
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, undated (Box 180, Folder 9)
- RG 22.26. Center for Labor and Employment Law, 2014
  - Labor & Employment Law Newsletter, May 2014
    NYU Labor & Employment Law is the Center for Labor and Employment Law's newsletter. It includes reporting on recent programs, awards for Board Members, obituaries, judicial reviews, and articles on employment and labor law. The PDFs of newsletter date from Fall 2007-Fall 2010.
- RG 22.27/RG 22.28. Prosecution Center/Peter L. Zimroth Center on the Administration of Criminal Law, 2014-2015
  - Center on the Administration of Criminal Law Facebook, May 2014-May 2015
    Facebook page for the Center on the Administration of Criminal Law. The page contains event listings, news about Executive Directors Nancy Hoppock and Anthony Barkow, images from events and conferences, fellowships, and other news.
  - Center for Research in Crime and Justice Blog, July 2014
    Blog for the Center for Research in Crime and Justice. It includes posts recapping the Hoffinger Criminal Justice Forum, book reviews, and awards.
  - Prosecution Center Twitter, May-July 2014
    Twitter feed for the Prosecution Center. Tweets are focused on the criminal justice system.
- RG 22.29. Engelberg Center on Innovation Law & Policy, 2014-2015
  - Engelberg Center on Innovation Law & Policy Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the Engelberg Center on Innovation Law & Policy. Posts include event listings, call for papers, the Center in the news, Drones & Aerial Robotics Conference information, Empirical Research Initiative, job opportunities, and other announcements.
  - Engelberg Center on Innovation Law & Policy Twitter, May 2014-May 2015
    Twitter feed for the Engelberg Center on Innovation Law & Policy. Tweet topics include wine tasting, open positions at the Center, New York Times v. Sullivan, copyright law, analysis of Supreme Court decisions, intellectual property, and conferences.
- RG 22.30. NYU Furman Center, 2011-2015
  - Furman Center for Real Estate & Urban Policy Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the Furman Center. The page includes links to articles on rent, affordable housing, parking, mass transit, construction, racism in housing, retrofitting for climate change, and affirmative action; reports by the Center; events at the Center; their newsletter Housing Starts; and job postings.
  - Furman Center for Real Estate & Urban Policy Twitter, May 2014-May 2015
    Twitter feed for the Furman Center. Contains tweets related to residential segregation, the rental landscape of New York City, affordable housing, compact housing, housing retrofits for climate change, rent stabilization, rezoning, and other information from their State of New York City Housing and Neighborhoods report.
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 2011 (Box 180, Folder 10)
- RG 22.31. U.S. Asia Law Institute, 2014-2015
  - U.S.-Asia Law Institute Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the U.S.-Asia Law Institute. The page features article written by or documenting the activities of founder Jerome Cohen, events sponsored by the Institute including the 2014 Bernstein China Symposium, job opportunities, photographs from events, links to summaries of events and rule of law news roundups, and links to articles on the rule of law in Asia.
  - U.S.-Asia Law Institute Twitter, May 2014-May 2015
    Twitter feed for the U.S.-Asia Law Institute. Many of the tweets are documenting the 2014 Bernstein China Symposium: Promoting Human Rights in China: Domestic and International Levers for Change. Tweets also document Jerome Cohen's activities as the founder and faculty director of the Institute.
- RG 23.0. Robert I. Grossman School of Medicine, 1842-2014
  - Collected Reprints from the Department of Experimental Surgery, 1915-1927 (Box 183, Folder 1-4)
  - The College of Medicine at War, circa 1941-1945 (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - The Complete Reporter, 1959 (Box 165, Folder 7)
  - Development News, 1983-1992 (Box 165, Folder 8)
  - Focus on Medical Activities, 1965-1973 (Box 181, Folder 2-15, Box 182, Folder 1-13)
  - Health Letter, 1987-1988 (Box 183, Folder 5)
  - Issues, 1972-1976 (Box 183, Folder 6)
  - The Medical Advance, 1946-1951 (Box 181, Folder 14, Box 195, Folder 2-4)
  - Medical Bulletin, 1936-1946 (Box 183, Folder 7-8, Box 184, Folder 1-8, Box 185, Box 186, Folder 1-3)
  - New York University Bulletin of the Medical Sciences, 1901-1902 (Box 187, Folder 1-3)
  - The New York University Lancet, 1842 (Box 186, Item 4, Box 187)
  - NYU Medical Center in the News, 1983-1989 (Box 167, Folder 7)
  - NYU Physician, 2009-2014 (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - Physician Information Network, 1979 (Box 188, Folder 2)
  - The Pulse, 1963 (Box 188, Folder 3)
  - Research News, 1988 (Box 165, Folder 9)
  - Research Report, 2009-2011 (Box 188, Folder 4)
  - Researches of the Loomis Laboratory, 1890 (Box 194, Folder 7)
  - Studies in Surgical Pathological Physiology from the Laboratory of Surgical Research, 1915 (Box 188, Folder 5)
  - Women's Health, 1998 (Box 188, Folder 6)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1866-1867, 1895-1896 (Box 188, Folder 7)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1921-1990 (Box 188, Folder 8-10, Box 189, Folder 1-9, Box 190, Folder 1-5)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Posters, 1965-1966 (Box 167, Folder 8)
- RG 23.2. NYU Post Graduate Medical School, 1962-1990
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1962-1990 (Box 190, Folder 6-8)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, circa 1990 (Box 165, Folder 10)
- RG 23.4. Institute of Environmental Medicine, 1962-1967
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Volume I and II -- Institute of Environmental Medicine, N.Y.U. Medical Center, 1962-1964 (Box 191, Item 1-2, Box 192, Item 1)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1962-1967 (Box 193, Folder 1-3)
- RG 23.5. Institute of Rehabilitation Medicine, 1959-1983
  - IPMR, 1959-1960 (Box 193, Folder 4)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1958-1983 (Box 193, Folder 5-9)
- RG 23.6. NYU Bellevue and Mills School of Nursing, 1925-1958
  - Research Activities, 1955-1958 (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1925-1951 (Box 194, Folder 2-4)
- RG 23.8. Veterinary College, 1917
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1917 (Box 194, Folder 5)
- RG 23.10. Institute of Industrial Medicine / Office of Industrial Liaison, 1953, undated
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1953, undated (Box 194, Folder 6)
- RG 24.0. School and Engineering and Science, 1902-1973
  - Collated Contributions and Papers Published from the College of Engineering Students and Faculty, 1934-1969 (Box 196, Folder 1-4, Box 197, Folder 1-6)
  - Engineering at the Heights, 1964-1972 (Box 198, Folder 1-2)
  - The Hex, circa 1954 (Box 198, Folder 3)
  - The Hexagon, 1949-1965 (Box 198, Folder 4-9)
  - Mall, 1952 (Box 198, Folder 10)
  - The New York University Engineer, 1902 (Box 198, Folder 11)
  - NYU Engineering Research Review, 1950-1962 (Box 199, Folder 1-2)
  - New York University Quadrangle, 1930-1949 (Box 199, Folder 3-5, Box 200, Folder 1-5, Box 201, Box 202, Folder 1-4)
  - New York University Quadrangle, 1944-1946 (Box 204, Item 1-2)
  - New York University Quadrangle, 1946-1948 (Box 205, Item 1-2)
  - New York University Quadrangle, 1948-1951 (Box 203, Folder 1-4)
  - New York University Quadrangle, 1950-1959 (Box 206, Folder 1-4, Box 207, Box 208, Box 209)
  - New York University Quadrangle, 1959-1972 (Box 210, Folder 1-5, Box 211, Folder 1-4, Box 212, Folder 1-7, Box 213, Folder 1)
  - The Student Engineer, 1942-1946 (Box 195, Folder 5)
  - The Uncivil Civil, 1934 (Box 213, Folder 2)
  - The Victory Engineer, 1944 (Box 195, Folder 5)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1916-1973, undated (Box 216, Folder 2-10, Box 217, Folder 1-5, Box 195, Folder 6)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Press Releases and Clippings, 1946-1972 (Box 213, Folder 3-10, Box 214, Folder 1-8, Box 215, Folder 1)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- News Clippings, 1954-1966 (Box 215, Folder 2-7, Box 216, Folder 1)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Air Pollution, circa 1955-1965 (Box 217, Folder 6-7, Box 218, Folder 1-3)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Chemical Engineering, circa 1955-1965 (Box 218, Folder 4)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Civil Engineering, circa 1955-1965 (Box 218, Folder 5-6)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Electrical Engineering, circa 1955-1965 (Box 219, Folder 1)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Data Computer, circa 1955-1965 (Box 219, Folder 2)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Industrial Engineering, circa 1955-1965 (Box 219, Folder 3)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Innovations and Inventions, 1965-1969 (Box 219, Folder 4)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Land Acquisition, Sterling Forest, circa 1960 (Box 219, Folder 5)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Mechanical Engineering, circa 1950s (Box 219, Folder 6)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Summer Computing Program, 1960-1965 (Box 219, Folder 7)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1969 (Box 219, Folder 8)
- RG 24.2. Daniel Guggenheim School of Aeronautics, 1924-1967
  - Technical Notes, 1931 (Box 220, Folder 1-2)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1924-1967 (Box 220, Folder 3-5)
- RG 24.3. Department of Meteorology, 1945-1970
  - Engineering Research Division Report, 1945-1950 (Box 220, Folder 6-9)
  - Meteorological Papers, 1948-1956 (Box 221, Folder 1-2)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1943, 1970 (Box 221, Folder 3-4)
  - Department of Meteorology and Oceanography -- Oceanic Research Survey, Department Information for Brochure, and Proposal for a Meteorology and Oceanography Center, circa 1950s (Box Shared University Archives 149, Folder 11)
- RG 25.0. College of Dentistry, 1867-ongoing